Dmytro Snisarenko

Software Engineer

Last update: January 18, 2024

Up-to-date version of CV is available at

https://MariamAlz.github.io/cv

Residence	★ Weesp, NL
LinkedIn	in <u>sneas</u>
GitHub	🗘 sneas
Mobile	+ 31645223717
Email	<u>dmytro@sneas.io</u>

I'm a full-stack developer with more than 15 years of experience. The setup for my last three projects happens to be AWS / Serverless / Lambda / NodeJS / Typescript for the backend, Angular / React / VanillaJS / WebComponents for the front end, Cypress / Jest / Endtest for testing, and CI/CD / Terraform for ongoing automation.

Professional Experience

Nov 2021 - Present

Vocably, Weesp, NL

Founder, Software Engineer

<u>Vocably</u> is a platform (extension and an app) that helps users to look up new words while surfing the web and study those words as flashcards on mobile.

As a founder and the only developer of Vocably, I'm responsible for:

- · Developing backend with AWS / GCP / NodeJS / Lambda / API Gateway / Cognito
- Developing mobile app with React Native
- Developing frontend/mobile experience (PWA) with Angular / Amplify
- Developing Chrome Extension with Vanilla / Web Components
- DevOps and CI/CD with CircleCI / Terraform / NodeJS / Zx / Bash
- · Testing with Jest / Cypress / Endtest.io
- · Market analysis, product marketing, cost and pricing analysis



Feb 2021 - Nov 2021

Athyria, Seattle, USA

Software Engineer

Completed two projects for John Deere.

- 1. A system that receives, stores, and processes operation metrics from different types of vehicles. Mainly AWS, NodeJS, Terraform, DynamoDB, Lambda
- 2. A sales tool that helps users to track, analyze, and predict various machinery metrics. Mainly Angular, OAuth, AWS, Terraform



Jul 2019 - Jan 2021

DAZN, Amsterdam, NL

Platform Engineer

High load media streaming platform.

Started as a front-end engineer at My Account team. Later as a full-stack/dev-ops engineer for the Developer Experience team which provided development, deployment, and automation tools for more than 60 teams and 500 people across DAZN Engineering.

Responsibilities:

- · Develop and maintain "My Account" section of the website. Mainly frontend with React / Mobx / Webpack / Jest
- Develop and maintain various deployment and development tools. Full stack with AWS / NodeJS / NextJS / Webpack / React / Redux



Reference: Cirpo Cinelly, Engineering Manager

Feb 2017 - Jun 2019

KLM Royal Dutch Airlines, Schiphol, NL

Senior Frontend Developer

Real time fault tolerant mobile application used by 330 KLM mechanics at Schiphol airport to perform between-the-flight aircraft maintenance. The application displays up-to-date KLM's fleet schedule and towing information, helps team leaders to manage teams, and provides the scope of work for mechanics.

Responsibilities:

• Incorporate business requirements into biweekly product increments

Achievements:

- · As a scrum team member, developed and launched a mobile app from the scratch
- Open source library as a solution to common lonic's problem. 1k weekly downloads in 2020



Reference: Önder Ceylan, Tech Lead

Jun 2014 - Feb 2017

Knab hypotheek, Amsterdam, NL

Senior Frontend Developer

Core front end developer of a fully automated mortgage advice system.

Started as a backend developer and eventually transferred to the frontend.

Responsibilities:

- · Developed new functionality
- · Conducted job interviews

Achievements:

- · Developed flexible registration process and 16 tools intended to gather detailed customer's legal and financial data
- · Component library as a result of collaboration with the design team
- · Introduced test driven development process with Karma and test automation with Protractor



Reference: Mark Sizoo, Tech Lead

upwork.com, Mountain View, USA

Senior Frontend Developer

Core frontend developer of the world's #1 freelance marketplace.

Responsibilities:

- · Developed A/B tested functionality for company's crucial business component: Job Posting Engine
- · Conducted job interviews
- · Facilitated onboarding process

Achievements:

- · Developed and successfully launched job post engine: highly-configured job posting and rendering tool
- Introduced test driven development process into the organization's development flow



Reference: Sean Kane, Vice President of Engineering

Career insights

2010 - 2012

Full stack freelancer (PHP, JS, SQL, Linux, CI/CD).

Successfully completed multiple small and middle-sized projects. Received <u>positive feedback</u> from all of my clients. Reviews are available <u>here</u>. Must be registered user to read all the reviews. Sorry.

2005 - 2010

Junior/middle full-stack developer (PHP, JS, SQL, Linux).

Significant experience was acquired while working on GameWatcher and RecordNerd.com.

2000 - 2003

Worked as visual designer for a local TV channel. Acquired passion for objects composition, color matching and animation.

Education

Masters degree in Computer Engineering. Sevastopol State Technical University [2002 - 2007]

Certifications

- aws AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate Jan 18, 2019
- C Professional Scrum Master I Apr 2, 2018
- React Nanodegree Dec 27, 2017
- PHP 5.3 Jan 24, 2011

Additional experience

- Some of my interests and hobbies revolve around GitHub and open source community.
 A complete list of side/hobby projects: https://github.com/sneas
- (Not so)Active member of developer communities
 - toster.ru/user/search (Russian speaking community)
 - stackoverflow.com/users/379949/sneas
 - <u>ru.stackoverflow.com/users/272582/sneas</u> (Russian speaking community)

Categories: Javascript Angular React Typescript